<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Impact Framework on Independent Impact</title>
    <link>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Impact Framework on Independent Impact</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Capabilities &amp; Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/active-capabilities-and-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/active-capabilities-and-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-capabilities&#34;&gt;Current Capabilities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Independent Impact already operates several production-grade components:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hedera Consensus Service integration&lt;/strong&gt; – Registration events, project submissions, validation checkpoints, and credential issuances are immutably sequenced on HCS.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity and access&lt;/strong&gt; – Participants can register, associate decentralised identifiers (DIDs), and earn role-based permissions aligned with their reputation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project design document workflow&lt;/strong&gt; – Project developers draft, submit, and revise PDDs with validators providing paragraph-level feedback until approval.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credential issuance&lt;/strong&gt; – Completed validations and verifications result in verifiable credentials that downstream partners can inspect and trust.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-progress&#34;&gt;In Progress&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reputation system&lt;/strong&gt; – Weighted indicators for projects, methodologies, and participants will surface on public profiles so collaborators understand assurance levels at a glance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First mile data collection&lt;/strong&gt; – Tooling for local field agents to capture photo, sensor, and survey evidence is under construction, anchoring submissions with verifiable provenance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-powered impact browser&lt;/strong&gt; – Natural-language search, contextual explanations, and auto-generated queries will help stakeholders explore the growing body of impact data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;planned-expansions&#34;&gt;Planned Expansions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indicators &amp;amp; metrics library&lt;/strong&gt; – A shared registry where subject-matter experts publish, debate, and finalise impact indicators and metrics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methodology development workspace&lt;/strong&gt; – Collaborative tooling for authoring methodologies, tracking revisions, and approving final versions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapid implementation toolkit&lt;/strong&gt; – Templates, training materials, and monitoring dashboards that help community projects get up and running quickly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public reporting platform&lt;/strong&gt; – Rich discovery and reporting interfaces so regulators, funders, and the public can interrogate verified outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We review roadmap priorities with partners on a rolling basis. Which capabilities should we accelerate?&lt;/em&gt; Reach out via the contact page to share requirements or to join a pilot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural Principles</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/architectural-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/architectural-principles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;balancing-openness-and-quality&#34;&gt;Balancing Openness and Quality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Independent Impact is founded on the ideal of mass participation in generating shared benefits for all. The platform removes barriers for new contributors while ensuring that quality signals guide the most consequential decisions. Every agent and control earns reputation through community assessment, and that reputation determines the responsibilities they can assume. These principles inform both the software architecture and the governance model that run the platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design System</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/design-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/design-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundations&#34;&gt;Foundations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Independent Impact’s visual language lives alongside the Hugo project so that marketing pages and product documentation stay in sync. Core design tokens are defined in &lt;code&gt;assets/css/main.css&lt;/code&gt; and surfaced to Tailwind through &lt;code&gt;tailwind.config.js&lt;/code&gt;, making colour and spacing choices available as semantic utility classes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour palette&lt;/strong&gt; – Brand blues (&lt;code&gt;--brand-blue-500/700/800&lt;/code&gt;), trust navy, verify green, accent cyan, and warning amber sit alongside neutral background, surface, and border tokens. These variables drive Tailwind colour aliases (for example &lt;code&gt;bg-surface&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;text-body-2&lt;/code&gt;), keeping templates expressive without hard-coded hex values.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typography&lt;/strong&gt; – The default sans-serif stack uses Inter for body copy and Plus Jakarta Sans for headings. Tailwind’s &lt;code&gt;font-sans&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;font-heading&lt;/code&gt; utilities map to these families, while prose components rely on the typography plugin for readable long-form content.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spacing and layout&lt;/strong&gt; – A shared &lt;code&gt;.container&lt;/code&gt; class sets max-width and horizontal padding, and &lt;code&gt;.section&lt;/code&gt; governs vertical rhythm. Custom utilities such as the rounded CTA pill (&lt;code&gt;.btn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.btn-primary&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.btn-secondary&lt;/code&gt;) give consistent interactivity across pages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;components-and-patterns&#34;&gt;Components and Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tailwind component layers declare navigation pills, feature cards, highlight blocks, and CTA sections. Shortcodes in &lt;code&gt;layouts/shortcodes/&lt;/code&gt; consume these styles to render heroes, feature grids, testimonials, and team listings without repeating markup. When new marketing blocks are required, authors can extend the existing layers or compose utilities, ensuring additions remain visually aligned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact Workflows</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/impact-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/impact-workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;operational-flow&#34;&gt;Operational Flow&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Independent Impact structures the lifecycle of impact claims from initial project conception to tokenisation. Workflows are transparent by default, and each stage leaves an auditable trail linking artefacts, responsible agents, and verification outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-design-and-submission&#34;&gt;Project Design and Submission&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementers prepare project design documents (PDDs) that describe planned interventions, impact pathways, methodologies, and data requirements. These artefacts are stored on IPFS and referenced within the platform so reviewers can trace every assumption and data source.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Architecture</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/technical-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:1313/impact-framework/technical-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;architectural-principles&#34;&gt;Architectural Principles&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Independent Impact implements technologies that reinforce transparency and accountability at every layer of the impact lifecycle. The stack is intentionally modular so the platform can incorporate new methodologies, data sources, and assurance requirements without sacrificing integrity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hedera-consensus-service&#34;&gt;Hedera Consensus Service&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hedera Consensus Service captures an immutable, ordered log of platform events. This journal confirms when artefacts were submitted, who evaluated them, and what decisions were taken. It underpins dispute resolution by providing a shared timeline of actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
