<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Independent Impact</title><link>http://example.org/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Independent Impact</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://example.org/aboutus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/aboutus/</guid><description>History Independent Impact grows from a decade of experimentation in verifiable impact accounting. Highlights include:
Aartum Whitepaper – articulated the vision that unique cryptographic representations of verified communal benefits could function as symbols of value, while calling out veracity as the central challenge for blockchain-based impact ecosystems. Read the original paper at aartum.io/pdf/aartum_programme_whitepaper_ver5. AIAO Ontology – collaborative work in the Hyperledger Climate Action and Accounting SIG to define a foundational ontology for anthropogenic impact accounting, enabling comparison across methodologies and metrics.</description></item><item><title>About Independent Impact</title><link>http://example.org/company/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/company/</guid><description>Mission Independent Impact enables communities to report, quantify, and verify human impact in a radically open and transparent manner. The platform does not prescribe what outcomes must look like; instead, it ensures anyone can understand precisely what every tokenised impact or verifiable credential represents. Participants choose the metrics, methodologies, and assurance levels that fit their context while relying on shared transparency to build confidence.
Participation Independent Impact invites new participants as implementers, validators, verifiers, and methodology developers.</description></item><item><title>Access &amp; Participation</title><link>http://example.org/pricing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/pricing/</guid><description>Participation Model Independent Impact is built to serve a wide community of practitioners, verifiers, and buyers who need confidence in the integrity of impact claims. Rather than traditional software pricing tiers, participation is governed by reputation and the responsibilities each participant assumes.
Reputation-Based Access Roles on the platform—such as implementer, validator, verifier, or methodology developer—carry minimum reputation requirements. Meeting those requirements grants access to associated tools and workflows. Do we have specific thresholds or examples that illustrate how reputation unlocks new capabilities?</description></item><item><title>Data Stewardship</title><link>http://example.org/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/privacy/</guid><description>Commitment to Transparency Independent Impact is built on transparency, yet we have not finalised a public-facing privacy and data stewardship statement. The platform combines decentralised identifiers, verifiable credentials, and distributed storage, which means roles and responsibilities for personal and project data must be clearly articulated.
Information We Need to Publish Data collection practices – What personal or organisational information do we collect during onboarding and participation? Storage and retention – How long are artefacts, credentials, and user records retained, and what options exist for redacting sensitive information while preserving auditability?</description></item><item><title>Impact Indicators &amp; Methods</title><link>http://example.org/impact-indicators-and-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/impact-indicators-and-methods/</guid><description>Why methodologies matter Impact accounting is only as strong as the methodologies that underpin it. Independent Impact stewards open, peer-reviewed frameworks that explain how outcomes are measured, which data sources are required, and what quality controls apply. The Anthropogenic Impact Accounting Ontology (AIAO) and the related Impact, Claim, and Information Communication ontologies provide the semantic backbone that lets every participant interpret results consistently.
Building reliable indicators Methodologies published on the platform describe:</description></item><item><title>Impact Workflows</title><link>http://example.org/features/impact-workflows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/features/impact-workflows/</guid><description>Operational Flow Independent Impact structures the lifecycle of impact claims from initial project conception to tokenisation. Workflows are transparent by default, and each stage leaves an auditable trail linking artefacts, responsible agents, and verification outcomes.
Project Design and Submission Implementers prepare project design documents (PDDs) that describe planned interventions, impact pathways, methodologies, and data requirements. These artefacts are stored on IPFS and referenced within the platform so reviewers can trace every assumption and data source.</description></item><item><title>Participate</title><link>http://example.org/careers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/careers/</guid><description>Join the Independent Impact Community Independent Impact is designed for mass participation. Whether you build projects on the ground, review methodologies, or validate data, there is a pathway for you to contribute to verifiable human impact.
How You Can Contribute Implementers bring forward projects and interventions, documenting their plans and results so they can be evaluated transparently. Validators review project design documents and methodologies to confirm that the proposed evidence and controls are sound.</description></item><item><title>Participation &amp; Governance</title><link>http://example.org/features/participation-governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/features/participation-governance/</guid><description>Balancing Openness and Quality Independent Impact is founded on the ideal of mass participation in generating shared benefits for all. The platform removes barriers for new contributors while ensuring that quality signals guide the most consequential decisions. Every agent and control earns reputation through community assessment, and that reputation determines the responsibilities they can assume.
Roles Across the Lifecycle Implementers submit projects and carry out interventions, providing the data needed to establish impact.</description></item><item><title>Platform Architecture</title><link>http://example.org/features/platform-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/features/platform-architecture/</guid><description>Architectural Principles Independent Impact implements technologies that reinforce transparency and accountability at every layer of the impact lifecycle. The stack is intentionally modular so the platform can incorporate new methodologies, data sources, and assurance requirements without sacrificing integrity.
Hedera Consensus Service Hedera Consensus Service captures an immutable, ordered log of platform events. This journal confirms when artefacts were submitted, who evaluated them, and what decisions were taken. It underpins dispute resolution by providing a shared timeline of actions.</description></item><item><title>Project Developers</title><link>http://example.org/project-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/project-developers/</guid><description>Start with transparent design Independent Impact welcomes projects that can articulate how activities lead to measurable human outcomes. When you submit a Project Design Document (PDD), explain:
The communities you collaborate with and how they shape priorities. The impact indicators and methodologies you plan to apply. Data collection plans, including how evidence will be captured and stored immutably. The reputation you or your partners already hold on the platform. Prepare your submission package Every PDD should be accompanied by verifiable artefacts.</description></item><item><title>Report Impact</title><link>http://example.org/report-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/report-impact/</guid><description>How to engage Whether you are developing a new project, authoring a methodology, or offering validation expertise, Independent Impact wants to hear from you. Use this page as your checklist before reaching out:
Summarise your initiative – Outline the community, outcomes, and timeframe you are working toward. Reference your methodology – Link to existing guidance or describe the evidence you plan to collect. List collaborators – Include participating organisations, local partners, and any validators already involved.</description></item><item><title>Terms &amp; Licensing</title><link>http://example.org/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/license/</guid><description>We have not yet published licensing or terms of use information for Independent Impact. To help stakeholders understand how they can use the platform and its artefacts, we need clarity on several points:
What legal entity operates Independent Impact, and under which jurisdiction? Is platform access governed by service terms, community charters, or open-source licences? How are methodology contributions, data submissions, and generated tokens licensed for reuse? Do validators, verifiers, or buyers agree to specific codes of conduct or liability limitations?</description></item><item><title>Validators &amp; Verifiers</title><link>http://example.org/validators-and-verifiers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/validators-and-verifiers/</guid><description>Upholding assurance Validators and verifiers ensure that every impact credential is grounded in transparent evidence. Independent Impact records evaluation workflows on the Hedera Consensus Service so that your assessments remain immutable and auditable. Before you accept an assignment, review:
The methodology in scope, including reputation requirements for evaluators. Documentation stored on IPFS or linked repositories. Any conflict-of-interest disclosures from the project team. Running your review When validating or verifying a project:</description></item></channel></rss>