<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Features on Independent Impact</title><link>https://independentimpact.org/features/</link><description>Recent content in Features on Independent Impact</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://independentimpact.org/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Impact Workflows</title><link>https://independentimpact.org/features/impact-workflows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://independentimpact.org/features/impact-workflows/</guid><description>Operational Flow Independent Impact structures the lifecycle of impact claims from initial project conception to tokenisation. Workflows are transparent by default, and each stage leaves an auditable trail linking artefacts, responsible agents, and verification outcomes.
Project Design and Submission Implementers prepare project design documents (PDDs) that describe planned interventions, impact pathways, methodologies, and data requirements. These artefacts are stored on IPFS and referenced within the platform so reviewers can trace every assumption and data source.</description></item><item><title>Participation &amp; Governance</title><link>https://independentimpact.org/features/participation-governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://independentimpact.org/features/participation-governance/</guid><description>Balancing Openness and Quality Independent Impact is founded on the ideal of mass participation in generating shared benefits for all. The platform removes barriers for new contributors while ensuring that quality signals guide the most consequential decisions. Every agent and control earns reputation through community assessment, and that reputation determines the responsibilities they can assume.
Roles Across the Lifecycle Implementers submit projects and carry out interventions, providing the data needed to establish impact.</description></item><item><title>Platform Architecture</title><link>https://independentimpact.org/features/platform-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://independentimpact.org/features/platform-architecture/</guid><description>Architectural Principles Independent Impact implements technologies that reinforce transparency and accountability at every layer of the impact lifecycle. The stack is intentionally modular so the platform can incorporate new methodologies, data sources, and assurance requirements without sacrificing integrity.
Hedera Consensus Service Hedera Consensus Service captures an immutable, ordered log of platform events. This journal confirms when artefacts were submitted, who evaluated them, and what decisions were taken. It underpins dispute resolution by providing a shared timeline of actions.</description></item></channel></rss>